残酷な天使のように 少年よ 神話になれ
作詞・作曲・編曲 初音ミク
青い風が今 胸のドアを叩いても
私だけをただ見つめて 微笑んでるあなた
そっと触れるもの 求めることに夢中で
運命さえまだ知らない 痛い気な瞳
だけどいつか気づくでしょう その背中には
遥か未来 目指すための羽があること
残酷な天使の帝政 窓辺からやがて飛び立つ
ほとばしる熱いパッドスで 思い出を裏切るなら
この空を抱いて輝く 少年よ 神話になれ
ご視聴ありがとうございました
Unit-1's interlock circuit has been cut off
What about the eject signal?
all codes are being blocked from inside the plug
it's not being accepted
look Shinji if we hadn't taken over you would have been killed
that's not the point
maybe but it's the truth
stop pushing me damn it
don't push me anymore
Unit-1 has 185 seconds of power left
that's enough to destroy at least half of headquarters
he'll do it too the way he is right now
Shinji will you listen to us?
if the commander hadn't made the decision to engage the dummy plug
everyone here could have been killed
I said that's beside the point damn you
my father tried to kill Toji and he did it using my hands
that bastard
Father! I know you're there
say something answer me
increase the entry plug's LCL pressure to its maximum level
what?
I have no time to waste on a petulant child
I've still got a direct control circuit!
damn
you
the liquidification of the right breast has been completed
we'll start cleansing the bottle to commence from 3-0 on schedule
how are you?
I'm not hurt enough to stop doing my job
I couldn't lie in bed during an emergency like this
so what did they end up doing with Shinji?
it's my understanding that they had to cut the escape hatch open with a laser cutter and remove him forcibly
this sucks
I'm afraid that this time
he's really finished
he can't talk his way out of this
idiot
is he alright?
he wasn't injured if that's what you mean
he's probably imagining that it was all a dream
a dream?
yeah
don't tell me you don't dream either
what?
Xinjiang? Why is he in the hospital there next to me? Is this the same hospital where my sister is?
Shhh. Shhh.
Huh? Shinji and Ayanami?
Ikari, why did you do that?
Because I couldn't trust him. My father betrayed me, Rei.
Even though I was finally able to talk to him, he still doesn't understand me at all.
Did you try to understand him? His feelings?
I used to try.
Why don't you try to understand him?
I said I did!
You're running away from the truth because it's ugly.
Why not? What's wrong with running away from reality if it sucks?
This is weird. What are those two arguing about?
This is by special permission. You've got exactly five minutes.
Thank you.
Hey, it's the class rep.
Tsuzahara, how are you feeling?
Lousy. But at least I'm still alive.
That's strange. I thought Shinji was here. Was that just a dream?
They took him out of here yesterday. You slept for three days, Toji.
I did? Three days? Did you...?
No, I've only been here a little while. They wouldn't let me. I mean, I came as the class representative, you know.
Of course, I know that.
Do you really?
I'm sorry. I didn't get to eat the lunch you made.
Don't worry about it. It's all right. Just wish I could bring you a lunch here, but it's not allowed.
First rep, would you do me a favor?
Uh-huh.
Would you tell my sister that there's nothing wrong with me?
Shinji Akari? Commander wants to see you.
Disobeying orders. Using an Ava for personal vendettas. Childish intimidation. These are all criminal offenses. Do you have anything to say?
Yes. I don't want to pilot an Ava anymore. And I don't want to stay here either.
Well then, you may leave.
Yes. I'll go back to my old teacher.
So, you're running away again.
You disappoint me. I assume that we will never meet again.
Yes. That's my intent.
This is me. Erase the third child's Ren. Ray will become Unit One's designated pilot, with the dummy plug as backup.
Welping for a wanderer.
Wae, where?
Wae quite's time.
Wae done when it's automatic再びenge had a dry lebency.
Wae, where do you buy a 2013 program?
Hey, Shinji! Can you hear me?
Is it true that you're leaving?
It is true, isn't it?
But why?
Why are you running away again?
I admired you.
I envied you.
You're different from us.
Damn.
Even Toji became a pilot.
Wrong.
This line is monitored.
For security reasons, we have terminated this call.
We appreciate your cooperation.
I don't think Asuka will be coming.
She must be pretty disgusted with me.
Yes, she didn't even ask me to say goodbye to you.
That sounds like her.
That's good.
It's going to be hard if you keep hiding your anger like that.
That's your philosophy, Misato.
I can't live the way you do.
Well, as I'm sure you know, there will be a lot of restrictions placed upon your activities from now on.
Yes, I know that.
But...
Yes?
Let me ask you one thing.
Why was Toji chosen to be the fourth child?
It would seem that all of the students that are in your class are fourth-level candidates, Shinji.
I just found out myself that it was yet another elaborate fabrication.
All of them?
All of my classmates?
Shinji, about Suzuhara, that was a mistake that can't be mended with words alone.
But I have to be honest with you.
I was projecting all of my dreams, hopes, and purpose onto you.
I know that it's been a huge burden for you.
But we, and by that I mean everyone at Nerve, have had no choice except to place our future in your hands.
I want you to remember that.
The end justifies the means?
Yes, that's how it is.
And another thing.
I'll be leaving your passcode to headquarters and your room as they are.
What's the point?
Get rid of them.
It's over now.
I won't pilot that thing.
This is the real Shinji talking.
I've never heard him sound so certain about anything before.
A special state of emergency has been declared for the Tokai region.
All residents must evacuate to their designated shelters immediately.
An angel?
All personnel go to first stage battle stations.
Prepare for ground-to-air intercept.
Target status.
It's broken through our perimeter.
The Kamagataki defense line has been shattered.
The first 18 layers of armor have been breached.
I don't believe it.
18 layers destroyed in one shot.
The A-Bus can't deploy fast enough to intercept up top.
Position unit two for combat inside the geo front, directly in front of headquarters.
Aska will snipe the target as soon as it breaks into the geo front.
Zero status?
Unit zero is in the AT field neutralization zone, Major.
But the left arm still hasn't been regenerated.
Then it's not ready for combat yet.
Send Ray out in unit one.
Prepare a dummy plug as the backup system.
Right.
Initiating entry.
Charging LCL.
Commencing A-10 nerve connection.
The pulse flow is reversing.
Unit one's refusing the neural connection.
Is that possible?
Ikari?
Yes.
Is it refusing me?
52.
58.
Abort the activation.
Send Ray out an Ava unit zero.
Reactivate unit one with the dummy plug.
But unit zero isn't ready.
It's not a problem.
I can go.
Ray?
If I die, I can be replaced.
I made up my mind.
I swore I'd never pilot that thing.
Hey, you there.
What are you doing?
Get in the shelter, quickly.
It's no use.
One more hand in the armor will be completely destroyed.
I'm counting on you, Aska.
Here it comes.
I can beat this angel, even without Shinji, the hero, here to help out.
Damn you!
Shice!
Next!
I'm sorry.
I'm neutralized against A-team field, aren't I?
Why won't you collapse, damn you?
This can't be happening.
I can't lose again.
Not again.
Oh my God!
The Dolphin Shrine was!
Aska, no!
Disengage your nerve connections now!
No!
Evacuation training?
What are you, stupid?
That stuff's not for pilots, like us.
Direct hit on the 8th block.
Abandon the 6th shelter.
All survivors go to the 3rd shelter.
Unit 2 is severely damaged.
It can't continue combat.
How's Aska?
She's alive.
Verdummed.
The Angel has started moving again.
What's Unit 1's status?
Dummy plug upload completed.
Pro insertion completed.
Initiate contact.
Roger.
What?
The pulse has vanished.
It's refusing the dummy plug.
Unit 1 won't activate.
The dummy and Ray?
We're both refused.
Futeski, take the con.
Evacuate the casualties to the 6th block.
Uninjured!
Go to the 3rd shelter!
Hey!
This way!
Hey, what are you doing?
You want to die?
Aska.
Hey, Shinji!
Kaji?
What are you doing here?
That's my line.
What are you doing here, Shinji?
I...
I decided that I'd never pilot an EIBA again.
Since I decided that...
Oh, really?
Well, to answer your question,
since my other job became public knowledge,
I'm off the combat roster.
So, here I am, sprinkling.
At a time like this?
What better time?
Although I'd rather be between Misato's melons,
this is a place I'd like to be when I die.
Die?
That's right.
It is said that if an angel comes into contact with Adam,
who lies sleeping beneath this very ground,
humanity will be eradicated in the 3rd impact.
The only thing that can stop this
is the one thing that has power equal to an angel's.
Evangelion.
Ayanami!
With no rifle!
It's an N2 mine!
Ray!
AT field, full power.
Unit zero.
Ray!
Oh, dear God.
Shinji, the only thing I can do is stand here in water.
But you, you have something that you can do,
that only you can do.
Nobody is forcing you.
Think for yourself and make that decision by yourself.
Think about what you have to do now.
Think about no longer having any regrets.
Direct hand on the 3rd foundation!
The final armor plate is about to...
Dammit!
It's open!
The main shout is completely open!
Isn't Unit 1 ready yet?
It's still refusing the deli plot!
It's not working!
No response detected!
Keep trying.
Repeat the process from step 108.
Let me pilot it!
Please!
Let me pilot Unit 1!
Father.
Why are you here?
I'm here because I'm the pilot of Evangelion Unit 1!
Shinji Ikari!
We've been breached!
Target is inside the main shaft!
It's advancing!
Where is it heading?
It's advancing directly towards Central Dogma!
It's coming here!
All personnel evacuate!
Repeat!
Eva Unit 1?
Shinji!
Aah!
Ah!
Let's go!
Launch the fit catapult!
Energy reserves depleted.
Unit 1 has completely drained its reserves.
The backup power supply isn't working.
Shinji.
Shinji!
Damn it!
Move!
Come on!
You goddamn piece of junk!
Move now and there's no point to any of this!
Damn it!
What's that?
Move!
Come on!
You've got to move now!
Everyone will be killed!
I'm sick of it already!
Come on!
Move!
God damn you to hell you filthy stinky monster!
Huh?
It's... it's reactivated.
Oh, my God.
This is impossible.
It must be wrong.
How can Shinji's sync ratio with Unit 1 be over 400%?
It's finally happened.
It's aware.
Help.
It's eating... the angel.
It's eating... the S2 organ.
She's taking it into herself.
Maybe Unit 1 is... this.
It's breaking free.
Free of what?
Those plates weren't just armor.
They were also restraints.
Those bindings allowed us to control it.
But now the Ava is removing the web that binds it to our will.
The beast inside the Ava is free at last.
Unit 1's awakened and been set free.
Sele sure won't stay quiet for this.
Was this part of your scenario, Commander Ikari?
It's begun at last.
Indeed.
This is the beginning.
Blinded to the moon, and let me play among the stars.
Let me see what's free is like a dream in the animals, in the demons, in the demons.
It's begun at last.
Indeed.
This is the beginning.
It's begun at last.
Indeed.
This is the beginning.
Oh!
Another world, please be true.
Another world, I love you.